

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Costin Giumba



202H, Splaiul Independentei, Bloc 2 Ap. 17, Bucharest, Romania

(+40)727210191

costingmb@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/costin-giumba-07620b9b/

WhatsApp Costin Giumba, Instagram costin_giumba

Sex Male | Date of birth 17/07/1988 | Nationality Romanian

JOB APPLIED FOR POSITION PREFERRED JOB STUDIES APPLIED FOR

In the first place, I intend to gain professional experience and develop my career into one of these IT/Engineering areas of expertise: Networking, Automation, Security, Virtualization, SDN, Cloud Computing.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Support Engineer II

(from May 2018 - until February 2020) 1-year and 9 months

Ixia, Keysight Technologies Romania SRL, Bucharest, Romania Responsibilities:

- Providing technical support at expert level over the phone and email for Ixia's clients within the EMEA region.
- Reporting design flaws, identifying software issues and transfer problem issues into the issue tracking system with supporting log files and packet captures/traces using lxTracker.
- Assisting customers in using and configuring the software of Ixia Network Visibility hardware equipment, with an emphasis on Visibility products and features.
- Hands-on experience with the Ixia NVS and security products: taps, ibypass switches, Network Packet Brokers, Threat Armor.
- Assisting customers in using and configuring the software of Ixia IxANVL hardware equipment, concerning L4-L7 and L2-L3 protocols. Running RFC conformance test suites in order to validate feature functionalities of the units.
- Installing and troubleshooting virtual Taps solutions (CloudLens VM) using vmware cloud deployment on ESXi hosts, implementing distributed and standard virtual switches between multiple VMs.
- Effectively collaborating and communicating with worldwide support and dev engineering team
- Investigating, analysing and testing customer's problems in the lab using lxia software/hardware.
- Tracking and recording the transport of hardware equipment through internal procedures.
- Creating, following and investigating client requests raised in Salesforce application.
- Experienced installation, configuration and troubleshooting on Cisco ASR 1001x Router Series, Ubuntu and CentOS Linux OS distribution.

(from March 2016 - until May 2018) 2 years and 2 months

IoT Network Support Engineer

Vodafone Shared Services Romania SRL, Bucharest, Romania

Responsibilities:

- Performs monitoring and troubleshooting activities for the M2M Global Infrastructure in order to maintain the functioning state of the hardware and software systems, using the available tools.
- Performs troubleshooting and impact analysis on incidents which are tearing down the voice, sms, provisioning, reporting or data services (Voice CO, Voice CT, SMS-MO, SMS-MT, PDP context, LTE bearer session, Location Update, GPRS/LTE Attach etc.)
- Provides 24h/24h end-to-end technical support, gathers and analyses all the required logs and traces from the customer or monitoring systems during and post-fault investigations.
- Acting as a central joint point for all major incidents and coordinating them in order to ensure an action plan or a back-up plan is created and focused on restoring it within the SLA.
- Provides technical information to customers about events and alarms that affect services,



- using agreed methods of communications.
- Prepares major incidents reports, in order to be used by the problem and incident management teams.
- Works in compliance with the operational agreements to fulfil the key performance indicators
 of the service (speed, response time, error rate, delivered throughput).
- Performing data packet analysis using Wireshark in order to troubleshoot issues on both IP Backbone and Packet Switch networks as well analysing the IPSec tunnel configurations.
- Creates work instructions and technical operational procedures for the consolidation of knowledge and competencies within the team.
- Experience with IoT platform services, devices and applications, APIs working and troubleshooting (transferred through REST or SOAP web architectures).
- Basic scripting configuration of the web servers so that the customers have access to GUI and API.
- Experienced configuration and troubleshooting on Cisco ASR 5000 and 7200 PE series, Juniper MX960 PE routers, Cisco Nexus 7k and 9k Series Switches

(from July 2015 to October 2015) 3 months

QA Automation – Software Testing Engineer

Luxoft Professional Romania SRL, Bucharest, Romania

Responsibilities:

- Testing of IPv4 and IPv6 features on Avaya VOSS based platforms.
- Implements feature test plans for the VRRP protocol.
- Perform manual and automated software testing.
- Identify software issues and transfer problem issues into the issue tracking system with supporting log files and data using IBMs Clearquest and Quality Center tools.
- Create test reports for the VRRP protocol.

(from December 2012 to July 2015) 2 years and 7 months

Front Office Core IP and Transmission Network Engineer

Ericsson Telecommunications Romania SRL, Bucharest Responsibilities:

- Projects: Vodafone Netherlands, Orange Belgium and Luxembourg.
- Perform network monitoring and first level fault troubleshooting on the Core Network (Circuit Switching, Packet Switching, Core MPLS/IP Backbone, IMS, SDH and DWDM Transport domains)
- Trouble ticket handling (OneTM, PeopleSoft) creating and resolving network trouble tickets in a given time frame depending on the severity.
- Cooperation with Incident Management for high incident related faults, escalations fulfilling the customer's target SLA.
- Dispatching and coordination of the field engineers with work orders, in case of incidents occurred at sites that need local support.
- Assure changes/planned work activities in the network are approved and performed in the allowed time window, relate alarms with ongoing CRQs.
- Investigating internal Core Transmission and terrestrial 3rd Party Transmission faults including progressing faults with fiber optics or dsl link providers (Proximus, Mobistar Enterprise, Fabricom, B-Telecom).
- Responsible with the creation of technical and operational procedures within the team.
- Application tools used for investigation: OSS-RC, Netcool, Reflection X, U2000, NetCracker
- Experienced troubleshooting on Ericsson Smart Edge 800 and 1200 series, Huawei NE40E/NE80E service provider routers, Huawei ATN910 IP modems, Huawei DWDMs (OSN 6800 and 8800 series).

Front Office Radio Access Network Engineer

Ericsson Telecommunications Romania SRL, Bucharest (from March 2012 to November 2012) – 8 months

Responsibilities:

- Front Office RAN Engineer specialized in mobile cellular network working for United Kingdom, monitoring 24h/7days the GSM/UMTS/LTE networks, using fault management systems and specific NMS and performing analysis to identify the issues.
- Handling emergency situations in the Radio Access Network and escalation to the incident management and second line of support in case of major and critical incidents.
- Monitoring and analysing the key performance indicators (KPI) for the radio access and transmission access network.
- Investigating internal Access Transmission and terrestrial 3rd Party Transmission faults

Page 2 / 5



- including progressing faults with link providers.
- Surveillance and troubleshooting alarms and faults occurred in the radio access and transmission access network by raising trouble tickets.
- Dispatching and coordination of the field engineers with work orders, in case of incidents occurred at sites that need local support.
- Investigation of complex incidents and events on Ericsson BTS cabinets (RBS 3000 and 6000 series), Alcatel 3G cabinets, RNC 3820 series via sub-network management systems and peripheral systems and tools.
- Application tools used for investigation: Remedy, OneTM, OneFM, Netcool, Netviewer (MW Nokia Siemens).

Business or sectors: IT & Software, Telecom

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Date: from October 2011 to July 2013

Title of qualification awarded: Master's degree in Management of Networks and Services Engineering at the Faculty of Electronics, Telecommunications and Information Technology (Politehnica University Bucharest).

 Advanced Operating Systems, Computer Networks, Mobile Networks, Advanced Databases, Management of the Network Services, Programming Languages, Routing and Transmission in Wireless Networks.

Date: from October 2007 to July 2011

Title of qualification awarded: Bachelor Degree of Applied Electronics and Engineering at the Faculty of Electronics, Telecommunications and Information Technology (Politehnica University Bucharest).

 Signals and Systems, Information Transmission, Communication Systems, Mobile Communications, Digital Signal Processing, Computer Programming, Databases, Computer Systems Architecture, Basic Electronic Circuits, Digital Integrated Circuits.

Date: from September 2003 to July 2007

Title of qualification awarded: High School Diploma at the "Ovidius" High School, Constanta

- Specialization: Mathematics and Computer Science
- Mathematics, Computer Science, Physics, English.

Trainings:

- Network Visibility Inline, Out-of band, dynamic filters basics this course was followed at Ixia
- CCNP Route This course was followed at Bit Academy Bucharest
- Cisco Service Provider This course was followed at Bittnet Systems Bucharest.
- Redhat Linux System Adminstration. The certificate was released by Telecom Academy Bucharest
- BGP Fundamentals. The certificate was released by Ericsson Academy.
- Datacomm Networking. The certificate was released by Ericsson Academy.
- MPLS and and VPN fundamentals. The certificate was released by Ericsson Academy.
- PHP Web Development. The certificate was released by Telecom Academy Bucharest.
- Mobile Softswitch Solution (MGW and MSC). The certificate was released by Ericsson Academy.
- SmartEdge Redback R11 Basic Troubleshooting. The certificate was released by Ericsson Academy.
- DWDM Workshop. The certificate was released by Ericsson Academy. SDH Fundamentals.
 The certificate was released by Ericsson Academy.

Certificates:

Cisco Certified Network Associate 200-125 (CCNA) Certification - January 2018. ITIL Foundations for IT Service Management Certification - November 2013.

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

Romanian



Other language(s)

English

French

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2/Proficient User	C2/Proficient User	C2/Proficient User	C2/Proficient User	C2/Proficient User
C2/Proficient User				
A2/Basic User	B1/Independent User	A2/Basic User	A2/Basic User	B1/Independent User
	В	1/Independent User		

Levels: A1/2: Basic user - B1/2: Independent user - C1/2 Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Social skills and competencies

- Excellent team-working skills, good communication skills, adaptive to new situations.
- Proactive with the ability to work under strong pressure related to scale of business impact.
- True customer mind-set, aptitude for quickly learning technical and procedural topics.
- Driving force and proactive attitude, strong performance focus.

Organisational Qualities

■ Teamwork orientated, proactive, continuous learner

Job-related/Professional acquired skills

- Good knowledge of mobile communications of mobile communications, GSM/UMTS/LTE architectures, interfaces, signalling and protocols.
- Entry level on Linux operating system administration, bash scripting and network troubleshooting.
- Good understanding of Ethernet and IP Security network protocols.
- Advanced VLAN, IPv4/IPv6, ACLs filters configuration on the Cisco IOS, IOS-XR, Ixia NVOS on Network Packet Brokers.
- Using Cisco/Huawei/Juniper/Avaya CLI commands to perform basic router and switch configuration and verification.
- Core Packet Switch troubleshooting and configuration on equipment: GGSN, PGW, DNS, AAA and Diameter Servers.
- Good understanding of BGP, L3VPN concepts, IP Security.
- Using Cisco/Huawei/Avaya CLI commands to perform basic router and switch configuration and verification.

Technical skills and competencies

- Network Fundamentals: IP Backbone, Circuit and Packet Switched Topology Design, Network Management Systems.
- Concepts of Routing Protocols, LAN Switching and Wireless 802.11, VLAN 802.1q, STP, RSTP, Accessing the WAN, TCP/IP and OSI stacks.
- In-depth knowledge of fundamental internet standards encompassing DHCP, DNS, SMTP, SNMP, HTTP and other Application layer protocols.
- Configuring and troubleshooting Cisco routers and switches, routing protocols OSPF, BGP, VLANS, L3 VPNs, L2 VPNs, ACLs, IPv4 and IPv6.
- Configure and verify basic WAN serial connections including serial, Point-to-Point, PPPoE and Point-to-Multipoint.
- Development of Website pages, understanding database design and development, using HTML/ XHTML and CSS.
- Use of SQL language specific instructions aimed at inserting data, query, update and delete, modify and create tables and data access control.
- Reading, editing, modifying and querying databases with PHP.

Computer skills

- Entry-level on Linux operating system administration, bash scripting and network troubleshooting.
- Experienced-level with network simulation programs: Cisco Packet Tracer, GNS3 emulator and Wireshark network protocol analyser.
- Entry-level with programming languages: C, C++, Python, PHP, SQL, dev environments: Dev-C++ and MS Visual Studio.
- Mid-level with Web and Database programming development environments: MS SQL Server, MySQL Workbench, Oracle SQL Developer, Adobe Dreamweaver CS5, Microsoft Office tools (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook).

Hobbies

• reading sci-fi, psychology and fantasy books, football, sports and fitness, travelling.



Driving licence B Category